# TEJAS CHATURBHUJ

156, bajrang nagar, Dewas, 455001 | +919584570080 | tejaschaurbhuj87@gmail.com

# Summary

Adaptable, fast learner, open-minded, AI student. Working on Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Domain. Majorly worked on Deep Learning project at Robotronix India pvt Itd. Connected with start up Nextjr.tech and worked on content creation, Build overall serverless site with proper LMS system.

# Experience

# Python & ML Developer

09/2021 to Currently

#### Glasier Inc

- Engaged in creation of a data analytical dashboard with 3 level drill down graphs.
- Working on API creation of 3 level drill down dashboard, generation of predictive model with cleaning and visualizing of data.
- Creation of Machine Learning models
- Creation of python api's through Flask and calling python api's in reactis
- Python API creation and setup of server and linking with Firebase.

Technologies Used - Python, Machine Learning, RestAPI, ReactJS, Google Firebase

## **Web Developer Intern**

07/2020 to 07/2021

Nextjr - Indore, MP

www.nextjr.tech

Online coding classes for kids Grade 1 to Grade 5

- Planned website development, converting mock-ups into usable web presence with React, Bootstrap, html/css.
- Advanced web presence planning, implementing changes and integrating requested elements to streamline business operations.
- Integrating AWS amplify to create serverless site with use of DynamoDB as database while using GraphQL api to data transfer
- Developed LMS platform according to Customer Requirement.

Technologies Used - html/css, Bootstrap, ReactJS, nodeJS, AWS Amplify, GraphQL, DynamoDB

#### Data Science Intern

09/2019 to 09/2020

Robotronix India pvt Itd – Indore, MP

www.robotronix.co.in

Company works on Industrial Automation and Robotics

## • Dynamic Trajectory Prediction (With Team)

- Forecasting Pedestrian Trajectory with Machine-Annotation on a moving vehicle.
- Use of JAAD dataset for performing training where use of Yolo model for detection of pedestrian and use of RESNET18 to train the model
- Model give us accuracy upto 67% closer to our exact point

**Technologies Used -** Deep Learning, Transfer Learning, CNN

#### • Multi UAV Mapping and map merging (Individual Contributor)

- Project aim was to create a map of a simulated forest environment with multiple drones mapping each foret factor.
- Worked on ROS (Robot Operating System)
- Performed SLAM and Mapping on environment

- Created Simulation of environment through gazebo

Technologies Used - Robot Operating System, Gazebo simulation, SLAM algorithm

#### • Automated car driving by Lan Detection (Individual Contributor)

- Project aim was to detect lanes and autonomously move according to the road lane.
- Worked on Raspberry Pi
- Use of Computer Vision and ROI technology for LAN detection

**Technologies Used -** Python, Computer Vision, OpenCV

#### Education

#### **B.Tech Artificial Intelligence**

Sage University, Indore

12th CBSE (PCM + CS)

San Thome Academy, Dewas

10<sup>th</sup> CBSE

San Thome Academy, Dewas

**2018 - 2022** *CGPA: 8.74* 

2017 - 2018

Percentage: 86%

2015 - 2016

CGPA: 7.6

# Skills

- Artificial Intelligence
- Computer Vision
- ROS
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Python

- Tensorflow
- Data Analysis
- AWS Amplify
- Data Science
- Git
- ReactJS

## Certifications

- Professional Certificate in TensorFlow Developer by deeplearning.ai on Coursera
- TensorFlow: Data and Deployment Specialization (DeepLearning.Al)
- Deep Learning with Tensorflow IBM DL0120EN on Edx
- Huawei HCIA Al Associate (Certificate no. 010102001393808054931409)
- Google Analytics Professional Certification from Coursera

#### **Achievements**

2nd Position in Poster Competition organised by Microfocus

- Worked on a Project about Virtual Assistant
- Lead the team of 8 members and worked on Photoshop CC
- Engaged in Surveys and Researches to get public opinion about Virtual Assistant

## Hobbies/interests

Reading | Fitness | Mobile Games | Chess | Football

# Social Media

linkedin - <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejas87/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejas87/</a> instagram - <a href="https://www.instagram.com/tejas\_chaturbhuj/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejas87/</a>

twitter - <a href="https://twitter.com/tejas8720">https://twitter.com/tejas8720</a>